Finding Aid of the UW-Milwaukee University Relations Records, 1962-2001
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
UW-Milwaukee University Relations Records, 1962-2001
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee. University Relations. Office of the Vice Chancellor
UWM Archival Collection 96
7.2 cubic ft. (13 boxes and 1 oversize folder)
University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee Libraries, Archives Department
This collection contains the records from the Division of University Relations at the University of Wisconsin-Milwaukee. The majority of the records date from the late 1970s and are comprised of budget planning documents, correspondence, letters, memos, minutes, and personnel files. These records document the activities of University Relations which include public relations with the departments of the university, the surrounding community, and local government. Fund-raising efforts, news and publications, and budget planning are also documented in the collection.
The Division of University Relations has as its stated mission to build the university's reputation and brand and enhance relationships in the community. At the time of UWM's founding, University Relations consisted of a single office managed by a director. The Office was reorganized as a division in 1970, and in 1971, several departments were transferred under its authority: Alumni Relations, Financial Development, News and Publications, Speakers Bureau, and the Retired Faculty Association. The Campus Information Desk, UWM's main customer service phone line, was added to this Division as its own department in 1980.
By 1985, the Alumni Relations, Campus Information Desk, News Services, University Publications, Development (formerly Financial Development) remained, the Speakers Bureau and the Retired Faculty Association were phased out, and the Government Relations and Campus and Communications Relations departments were added. In addition to its formal communications to particular groups within and outside the university, University Relations publishes reports on how research conducted at UWM influences the local and national economies and political landscapes.
As of 2016, offices and departments overseen by University Relations include External Relations, University Communications and Media Relations, Web Strategic Planning, Campus Print and Copy Services, and Media Services, including campus photography and television services.
Directors of the Office of University Relations
1964-1966 Floyd C. Springer, Jr.
1967-1970 Theodore LaTour
Assistant Chancellors for University Relations
1970-1972 Lynn W. Eley
1972-1976 Donovan Riley
1976-1980 Frank A. Cassell
1980-1988 H. Carl Mueller
1988-1989 K. Woit
1990-2000 Sandra Hoeh-Lyon
Vice Chancellor of University Relations
2000- Tom Luljak
The files are organized alphabetically by committee name, personal name, or by subject, then chronologically.
The records of the Division of University Relations primarily consists of files relating to campus development, major campus events, or departments/organizations of interest to the Division. There is a particular emphasis on neighborhood relations in the collection, with numerous files on the subject and a run of the community newsletter, Notes to Neighbors, from 1975-1985. Many of the files detail plans for construction, renovation, or demolition of various campus properties, such as the 1973 Lapham Hall renovation or the construction of the Sandburg residence halls. Also included are files on campus committees of interest to University Relations, including the Advisory Committee on Minority/Disadvantaged Student Life, Faculty Orientation Committee, and the University Relations Faculty governance committee (on which the Assistant Chancellor had a permanent ex officio seat). There are also a small number of files of correspondence dealing with production of two of UWM's official publications, UWM Today and UWM Report.
Also included in the collection are a small number of administrative files of the Division, including Budget Planning Documents, Land Use and Zoning reports for various sites on and off campus, and general correspondence of the Assistant Chancellor.
An inventory of the personnel files in boxes 1-5 is available in the Archives case file.
Administrative/Restriction Information
The unclassified personnel files in boxes 1-5 are restricted in accordance with UWM Personnel File Policy S-42. Access is regulated by Section III.A.2 and III.A.3.
There are no access restrictions on the rest of the collection, which is open to all members of the public in accordance with state law.
Judy Andresen and Jacque Graveen transferred an accession of personnel files (1990-011) in August 1990. Judy Andresen transferred accession 1994-023 in August 1995. Jacque Graveen transferred accession 1995-018 in August 1995. Maureen Burke transferred an accession of personnel files (1997-032) in December 1997. Linda Kopp transferred accession 2001-054 in 2002. An unknown party transferred accession 2005-042 probably in 2005.
Contents List
- Records, 1962-2001, UWM Archival Collection 96; 7.2 cubic ft. (13 boxes and one oversize folder)
  - Advertising, 1980-1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Advisory Committee on Minority/Disadvantaged Student Life, 1977-1982 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action, 1993-1994, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Allied Health Building, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Alumni Association, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 4-5)
  - Alumni Relations, 1968-1972 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - American Geographical Society Collection
    - Fundraising, 1976-1981 (Box 6, Folder 7-8)
    - Task Force, 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Formal Opening, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Analysis of Problems and Opportunities at UWM, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Athletics Department, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Banner, undated (Box 9)
  - Basketball Promotion, etc., 1977-1979 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Berkman, Dave, 1984-1987 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Black Community Relations, 1979 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Blue Hole Parking, 1973-1975 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Budget Planning Document
    - 1981-1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - 1985-1986 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - 1986-1987 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - 1986-1989 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - 1987-1990 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - 1988-1991 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - 1993-1994 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - 1994-1995 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - 1995-2000 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Budget Review for 1995-1996, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Building Programs, General, 1974-1979 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Cable Television, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Cable Television, 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Campus Information Service, 1960-1978 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Case for UWM, Public Relations, 1978-1979 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Cedarburg Bog, 1964-1970 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Centennial, 1983-1985 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Centennial, 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Centennial Launch, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Chilled Water Project, 1970-1971 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Citizens Study Committee on Metropolitan Problems, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - City Planning Commission, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Civic Center Campus, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Coffee With the Chancellor, 1974-1986 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Columbia Hospital Parking Proposal, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Common Ground, UWM-WRIT Radio Show, 1976-1977 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Community Educational Programs, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Community Night, 1977-1986 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Community University Forum, 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Complaints, 1971-1981 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Continuing Education for Adults, 1968-1971 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence and Meeting Minutes, 1975-1979 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Correspondence
    - Assistant Chancellor's, 1991-2001 (Box 13, Folder 3-18)
    - Community and Government Relations, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 19-20)
    - Kenilworth Building, 1983-1986 (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Director's, 1963-1969 (Box 6, Folder 33-36)
  - Cramer Street and EMS building, 1973-1981 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Day Care Center, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Desegregation of Milwaukee Schools, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Downer Buildings, 1976-1979 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Downer Campus Shops, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Drop Policy, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - East Side Community Council, 1968-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
  - East Side Community Council, 1973-1980 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - East Side Issues Community Advisory Council, 1976-1980 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - East Side Issues Radio Show - WUWM, 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Elderly Housing, Sandburg Hall, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 5-6)
  - Engelmann Field, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - English Admission Requirements, 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Enrollment Limits for UWM, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Environment Impact Statements, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Experimental Program in Higher Education, 1969-1970 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Face to Face, Union Forum Series, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Facilities and Services, General, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Founding Fathers, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Fromkin Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Fromkin Panel, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Fry Case, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Fund Raising Guidelines, 1969-1979 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Great Lakes Marine Facility, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Griffin Land Use and Zoning Report, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Griffin Land Use and Zoning Report, 1978 (Oversize 1)
  - Half-Century Club, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Hartford Avenue Closing, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Hartford Avenue School, 1975-1978 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Hermenning Scholarship, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Honor Roll of Donors, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - Horton, Frank E., 1980-1985 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Information Desk, 1977-1984 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Kenilworth Building, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Kenwood Conference and Alumni Center, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Klotsche, J. Martin, 1978-1979 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Kunkle Care Center, Rededication, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Lakeside Community Council
    - 1960-1971 (Box 7, Folder 29-30)
    - 1974-1984 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1979 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Land Sales Legislation, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Lapham Hall Pamphlet, circa 1973 (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - Lapham Hall Renovation, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Law School, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Legislature, 1969-1973 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Lorinczi, Rhonda Goodkin, Research Attorney, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Manpower Council, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Marquette University, 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Maryland Avenue Houses, 1973-1974, 1978-1981 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - McKinley Marina, 1972-1979 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Media Access and Relations, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Medical College of Wisconsin, 1974-1981 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Merrill-Johnston-Greene Rededication, Correspondence, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Metropolitan Milwaukee Association of Commerce, 1977-1978 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Milwaukee Journal, 1974-1978 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Milwaukee Sentinel, 1979-1982 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Minority Student Committee, 1984-1985 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Model Cities Policy Commission, 1970-1972 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Model Cities Program, 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Multiple Model Preschool Program, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Native American Studies Program, 1982-1985 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Neighborhood Meetings, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Neighborhood Relations, 1973-1980 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Neighborhood Summer Recreation Program, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Neighborhood Traffic and Parking Concerns, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - New Faculty Orientation, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - News and Publications, 1970-1971 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Notes to Neighbors, 1975-1985 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Occupational Therapy, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Orientation, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Outstanding Student Scholarship, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Parking and Transit, 1976-1981 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Parking and Transportation, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Parking Facilities, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Physical Education and Recreation Building Opening, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Physical Education Building, 1973-1977 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Polish Studies, 1977-1986 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Popcorn Forum, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Preview of the University of Wisconsin Booklet, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Public Relations Committee, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Publications, 1978-1985 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Publications, Bureau of, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Publications Center, 1978-1982 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Publicity Flyers, 2014 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - Racine, City of, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Real Estate Holding Corporation, 1962-1968 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Recruitment Brochures, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Research Awards Ceremony, 1981-1982 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Research Foundation Pamphlet, undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Riverside Cluster, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Sandburg Hall as Halfway House, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Sandburg Halls, 1974-1981 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Satellite Enrollment Services Office, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Scheinfeld Foundation, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - School of Architecture, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - School of Nursing, 1969-1970 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - School of Nursing, Employer's Insurance Chair, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Single Fest, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Skateboarding Problem, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Slide Show, 1976-1986 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Southeastern Wisconsin Medical Center, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Speakers Bureau, 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Staff Meetings, 1975-1981 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Staff Meetings, 1988-1990 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Strategic Plan, 1996, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Student Association, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Student Financial Aid, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Student Retention Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Target M.D. Program, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Task Force on Enrollment Trends, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Teaching Award Winners, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Television Stations, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Title IX and UWM Grievance Procedures, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Tours, 1982-1983 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Transit/Transportation, 1980-1982 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Twentieth Anniversary Report, 1975-1978 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary, 1980-1981 (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Twenty-Fifth Anniversary, 1981-1982 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - U-Bus, 1974-1981 (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - U-Fest, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - University Relations Committee, 1980-1981, 1994-1996 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - University Relations, Organization, 1973-1977 (Box 8, Folder 49-50)
  - University Relations, Reorganization, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Urban Outreach, 1975-1977 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Urbanology Series, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - UWM Arboretum, 1965-1966 (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - UWM Eastside Transit Improvement Study, 1975-1979 (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - UWM Foundation, 1979-1984 (Box 8, Folder 41-43)
  - UWM Foundation Research Awards, 1979-1982 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - UWM Magazine, 1970-1972 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - UWM Report, 1978-1981 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - UWM Seal and Logo/Slogan, 1974-1976 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Vogel Dedication, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Wish Lists from Deans, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - WUWM-FM 90 Radio Station, 1977-1979 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Year 2000 Master Plan, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Zigman, Robert, 1975-1980 (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Zigman-Joseph-Skeen, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Zoning Information, 1977-1981 (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Zoning Map, UW-Milwaukee (Oversize 1)